The most frightening thing about Jacob Singer's
nightmare is that he isn't dreaming.
Jacob's Ladder is a drama, mystery, horror film directed by Adrian Lyne.
After returning home from the Vietnam War, veteran Jacob
Singer struggles to maintain his sanity.
Plagued by hallucinations and flashbacks, Singer rapidly falls apart as the
world and people around him morph and twist into disturbing images.
His girlfriend, Jezzie, and ex-wife, Sarah, try to help, but to little avail.
Even Singer's chiropractor friend, Louis, fails to
reach him as he descends into madness.
Jacob, played by Tim Robbins.
Jezzie, played by Elizabeth Peña.
Louis, played by Danny Aiello.
Michael, played by Matt Craven.
Paul, played by Pruitt Taylor Vince.
Geary, played by Jason Alexander.
Jacob's Ladder is a 1990 American psychological horror film directed by Adrian
Lyne, produced by Alan Marshall and written by Bruce Joel Rubin.
It stars Tim Robbins as Jacob Singer, an American infantryman whose experiences
during his military service in Vietnam result in bizarre hallucinations.
The supporting cast includes Elizabeth Peña and Danny Aiello.
Jacob's Ladder was made by Carolco Pictures ten
years after being written by Rubin.
The film garnered a cult following, and its plot and special effects became a source of
influence for various other works, such as the Silent Hill video game series.
A remake was released in 2019.
The film explores themes of vietnam veteran, new york city,
post-traumatic stress disorder (ptsd), experiment, nightmare.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.